A Guide to the Notebooks and Correspondence of James Branch Cabell, 1896-1928
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Notebooks and Correspondence of James Branch Cabell, 1896-1928
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
5947-j
This collection consists of 38 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was a gift on 1964 April 21.
Scope and Content Information
One notebook, kept from 1896 to 1904, contains miscellaneous notes by Cabell regarding his work, including a partial bibliography of his stories and a "Genealogy in Harper Stories, 1355-1559."
Another notebook (two copies) contains "jottings preliminary to The Majors and Their Marriages" with notes regarding the Aston, Ballard, Branch,Britton, Charles, Christian, Dancey, Field, Harris, Hartwell, Hubard, Jefferson,Macon, Marable, Mason, Patteson, Piersey, Seawell, Soane, Stephens, Turpin, and Waddill families. Finally, the collection contains correspondence, 1910-1926, between Cabell and Hugh Walpole and a few letters from Emily Clark to Cabell.
Contents List
- Notebook containing notes for The Majors and Their Marriagesn.d., AMsS. 128 p.
- Letters, The letters between Hugh Walpole and James Branch Cabell are Xerox copies, given by Mr. Cabell.
  - James Branch Cabell to Hugh Walpole 1910 Aug 22[1920], ALS. 4 p.
  - Walpole to J.B.C. 1915 Dec 3, ALS. 2 p.
  - Walpole to J.B.C. 1920 Mar 13, ALS. 3 p.
  - J.B.C. to Walpole 1920 Apr 18, ALS. 2 p.
  - Walpole to J.B.C. 1920 Apr 20, TLS. 1 p.
  - Walpole to J.B.C. 1920 Apr 25, ALS. 8 p.
  - Walpole to J.B.C. 1920 May 30, ALS. 4 p.
  - J.B.C. to Walpole 1920 Jun 5, TLS. 2 p.
  - Walpole to J.B.C. 1920 Jul 24, ALS. 2 p.
  - Walpole to J.B.C. 1920 Sep 21, ALS. 2 p.
  - J.B.C. to Walpole 1920 Nov 21, TLS. 2 p.
  - Walpole to J.B.C. 1920 Dec 17, ALS. 4 p.
  - Walpole to J.B.C. 1921 Mar 28, ALS. 6 p.
  - J.B.C. to Walpole 192l Apr 21, TLS. 1 p.
  - J.B.C. to Walpole 1921 Jun 17, TLS. 1 p.
  - J.B.C. to Walpole 1921 Sep 10, TLS. 1 p.
  - Walpole to J.B.C. 1922 Jul 24, ALS. 2 p.
  - Walpole to J.B.C. 1922 Sep 27, ALS. 1 p.
  - Walpole to J.B.C. 1922 Dec 25, Christmas card
  - Walpole to J.B.C. 1923 Mar 2, TLS. 1 p.
  - Walpole to J.B.C. 1923 [Apr 1], ALS. 2 p.
  - Walpole to J.B.C. 1923 May 20, ALS. 2 p.
  - Walpole to J.B.C. 1923 Jun 13, ALS. 4 p.
  - Walpole to J.B.C. 1923 Jun 27, ALS. 4 p.
  - Walpole to J.B.C. 1924 Jun 28, ALS. 6 p.
  - J.B.C. to Walpole 1924 Aug 19, TLS. 1 p.
  - Walpole to J.B.C. 1924 Oct 26, ALS. 4 p.
  - J.B.C. to Walpole 1925 Nov 10, TLS. 1 p.
  - Walpole to J.B.C. 1925 Dec 11, ALS. 4 p.
  - Walpole to J.B.C. 1926 Dec 18, ALS. 4 p.
  - Emily Clark Balch to J.B.C. [1927] Jun 2, ALS. 6 p.
  - Emily Clark Balch to J.B.C. 1927 Jul 4, ALS. 6 p.
  - Balch to J.B.C. [1928] Nov 11, ALS. 3 p.
  - Balch to J.B.C. 1928 Nov 19, ALS. 3 p.
  - Balch to J.B.C. Jun 7, ALS. 5 p.
  - Balch to Hunter Stagg n.d., ALS. 1 p.